David Brady

Charleston, SC (843) 439-4964 dgrbrady@gmail.com

Passionate Full Stack Software Developer offering seven years of experience with DoD systems, networks and security postures in Agile environments. Holds an active Top Secret security clearance (SCI eligible) and is DoD 8570 compliant, with an IAT II appointment letter. Focused on spearheading research and development efforts that drive technology and solutions forward. Stay current or be left behind. Enjoys a team culture of excitement, open communication and works best when not being micro-managed.

EXPERIENCE

Core4ce LLC, Charleston, SC — Software Engineer III

APRIL 2021 - PRESENT (Contract spot transferred from ECS to Core4ce)

ECS Federal LLC, Charleston, SC — Full Stack Software Developer

APRIL 2018 - APRIL 2021

Summary: Redesign client's monolithic Python 2.6 Pyramid web application into a Microserviced and Dockerized Angular 11 SPA (Single Page Application). Design forward facing RESTful APIs for client consumption of data. Implement unit tests with Cypress testing suite. Set up Gitlab Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) pipeline responsible for ensuring code quality, security and product delivery. Lead architect for new solutions; evaluate latest technology and current practices to offer the most informed solutions to suit the client's needs. Mentor and train junior developers on the team. Develop documentation, software tools, scripts, workflows and processes for other developers to use. Plan milestones for new apps and features by turning client requirements into tasks for developers to work.

Result:

Fielded and maintained 5 applications used to support cyber security operations. Architected 1 application for cyber security analysis of forensic events.

George Consulting, Charleston, SC — Systems Administrator

JULY 2015 - MARCH 2018

Summary: Responsible for troubleshooting, building, testing, configuring and deploying C4I and C2 systems for Naval customers to enable support of the P-8A aircraft. Systems supported include Microsoft Windows Server and Desktop operating systems, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, VMWare virtual infrastructure and ESXi server hosts and Cisco networking devices.

145th Cyber Warfare Co, SC Army National Guard, Eastover, SC — *Information Technology Specialist*

OCTOBER 2014 - MAY 2020

Summary: Perform purple team activities (collaborative effort between offensive and defensive cyber security measures) for web application penetration testing. Respond to

Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems, implement advanced Web Application

Firewall rules and perform Active Directory GPO hardening. Follow and enforce

SKILLS

Front end web tech:

- JavaScript/Typescript (ES6+, jQuery, Angular6+)
- NgRx, Akita, RxJS
- > HTML5
- CSS3, SCSS
- Material, Bootstrap, Tailwind
- Testing (Mocha, Jasmine, Chai, Cypress)

Back end web tech:

- Python 2.6+ WSGI (Pyramid/Jinja2, Flask)
- ➤ NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS
- > RESTful API design
- > Microservice architecture
- ➤ ORM (TypeORM)

Scripting:

- > Bash
- Python
- NodeJS
- Vimscript
- Lua

Containers:

- Docker
- Docker-compose
- > Harbor

Configuration:

- JSON
- > YAML

DoD data security and integrity policies. Practice and develop training agendas and battle drills for fellow soldiers to ensure unit readiness and technical expertise.

EDUCATION

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Marlboro County High School}, Bennetts ville, SC-Distinguished Honor Graduate \\ \end{tabular}$

JUNE 2013

Fort Gordon Cyber Center of Excellence, Augusta, GA — *Distinguished Honor Graduate*

JULY 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

EC-COUNCIL CERTIFIED ETHICAL HACKER - Certification:

ECC70407134980

Expiration: 10 August 2023

COMPTIA SECURITY+ CE CERTIFIED — Certification: XHDQZDKG3H1E1YEJ

Expiration: 27 May 2022

- > XML
- > .env

Editors:

- ➤ Neovim/vim ♥
- ➤ VS Code
- ➤ Notepad++

Other:

- Version control (git, GitHub, GitLab)
- > CI/CD
- > ESLint, Prettier
- Agile development (JIRA, Gitlab)
- > Excellent oral/written communication skills
- MSSQL, Postgres
- Monorepos (Nx)
- Nginx and NJS
- ➤ KeyCloak
- > Java (exposure)